<section id="maven_repositories_dependencyresolution">
	<title>Maven repositories and dependency resolution</title>
	<section id="maven_repositories">
		<title>Maven repositories</title>
		If you run a Maven build, Maven validates if you still have the
			most recent version of all required artifact dependencies and Maven
			plug-ins
			and if required it retrieves them from a Maven repository. A
			repository is a collection of project artifacts stored
			in a directory
			structure similar to the Maven
			coordinates of the project.
		
		
			Maven downloads these artifacts and plug-in into a local
			repository.
			The local repository is located in the home directory of
			the user in
			the
			<filename>.m2/repository</filename>
			folder. If an artifact or a plug-in is available in the local
			repository Maven uses it from their.
		
		 Maven uses a default remote repository location (http://repo1.maven.org/maven2) from which
			it downloads the core Maven plugins and dependencies. You can configure Maven to use
			more repositories and replace the default one. 
		
			If you run the
			<code>mvn install</code>
			command, the generated artifact is installed into the local Maven
			repository.
		
	</section>

	<section id="maven_dependencyresolution">
		<title>Maven dependency resolution and Maven reactor</title>
		Every project can define dependencies using the unique
			identifier
			(GAV) of the component it required to compile.
		
		
			<programlisting language="java">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="./examples/dependencies/dep.txt" />
			</programlisting>
		

		
			During a build, the Maven system tries to resolve the
			dependencies of
			the modules which are build. To resolve dependencies, Maven uses the
			following sources in the given order:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					Project which are included in the same Maven run
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					local repository
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					Maven central repository
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		

		
			The projects which are included in the same Maven run are also called
			the Maven
			<wordasword>reactor</wordasword>
			.
		
	</section>

</section>
