<section id="resetcommitsdef">
	<title>Use cases for git reset</title>
	<indexterm>
		<primary>git reset</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<section id="resetcommit_move">
		<title>Moving the HEAD and branch pointer</title>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>git reset</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<para>
			Sometimes you want to change the commmit your branch pointer is pointing to. The
			<code>git reset</code>
			command allows you to manually set the current HEAD pointer (and its associated branch) to a specified commit.
			This is
			for example useful to undo a particular change or to build up a different commit history.
		</para>

		
image::images/gitreset10.png[Git reset]
LARSLINEBREAK
		<para>
			All commits which were originally pointed to by the HEAD pointer and the commit pointed to by HEAD after the reset,
			are
			<wordasword>reseted</wordasword>
			, e.g., not directly visible anymore from the current HEAD and branch pointer.
		</para>
		<para>
			Via parameters you can decide what you happen to the changes in the working tree and changes which were included in
			the commits between the original commit and the commit now referred to by the HEAD pointer. As a reminder, the
			working tree
			contains
			the files and
			the staging area contains the changes which
			are marked
			to be included
			in the next
			commit.
			Depending on the specified parameters the
			<code>git reset</code>
			command performs the following:
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you specify the
						<parameter>--soft</parameter>
						parameter, the
						<code>git reset</code>
						command moves the HEAD pointer. Changes in the working tree will be left unchanged and all changes which were
						commited
						included in commits which are reseted are staged.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you specify the
						<parameter>--mixed</parameter>
						parameter (the default), the
						<code>git reset</code>
						command moves the HEAD pointer and resets the staging area to the
						new HEAD. Any file change between the original
						commit and the one you reset to shows up as modifications (or untracked files) in your working tree. Use this
						option to remove commits but keep all the work you have done. You can do additional changes, stage changes and
						commit again. This way you can build up a different commit history.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you specify the
						<parameter>--hard</parameter>
						parameter, the
						<code>git reset</code>
						command moves the HEAD pointer and resets the staging area and the
						working tree to the
						new HEAD. This effectively
						removes the changes you have done between the original
						commit and the one you reset to.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>

		<para>
			Via parameters you can define if the staging area and
			the
			working
			tree
			is
			updated. These
			parameters are
			listed in the
			following
			table.
		</para>
		<para>
			<table frame='all'>
				<title>git reset options</title>
				<tgroup cols='4' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
					<colspec colname='c1' colwidth="1*" />
					<colspec colname='c2' colwidth="2*" />
					<colspec colname='c3' colwidth="2*" />
					<colspec colname='c4' colwidth="2*" />
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry>Reset</entry>
							<entry>Branch pointer</entry>
							<entry>Working tree</entry>
							<entry>Staging area</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<row>
							<entry>soft</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>mixed (default)</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>hard</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
						</row>
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</table>
		</para>
		<para>
			The
			<code>git reset</code>
			command does not remove untracked files. Use the
			<code>git clean</code>
			command for this.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="resetcommit_path">
		<title>Not moving the HEAD pointer with git reset</title>
		<para>
			If you specify a path via the
			<code>git reset [path]</code>
			command
			,
			Git does not move the HEAD pointer. It updates the staging
			area
			or also
			the working tree depending on your
			specified option.
		</para>

	</section>

</section>
