<section id="rebase" role="wrapper">
	<title>Rebasing branches
	<section id="rebase_branches">
		<title>Rebasing branches
		
			LARSPRIMARYINDEX"git rebase"LARSPRIMARYINDEX
		
		
			You can use Git to rebase one branch on another one. As described,
			the
			`merge`
			command
			combines the changes of two branches. If you rebase a branch
			called A
			onto another, the
			`git`
			command takes the
			changes introduced by the commits of branch A and
			applies them based on the
			HEAD of the other branch. This way the
			changes in the other branch are also available in branch A.
		

		
			The process is displayed in the following picture. We want to
			rebase
			the branch called
			`branch_1`
			onto master.
		
		
image::img/gitrebase10.png[Rebasing a branch]
LARSLINEBREAK
		Running the rebase command creates a new commit with the changes
			of the branch on top of the master branch.
		
		
image::img/gitrebase20.png[Rebasing a branch result]
LARSLINEBREAK
		Performing a rebase does not
			create a merge commit.
			The final
			result for the source code
			is the same as with merge but
			the commit
			history is
			cleaner; the
			history
			appears to be linear.
		
		Rebase can be used to forward-port a feature branch in the local
			Git
			repository onto the
			changes of
			the master branch. This
			ensures that
			your
			feature is close to the tip of the upstream branch until it is
			finally
			published.
		
		If you rewrite more than one
			commit by rebasing, you may have to
			solve conflicts per commit. In this case the merge
			operations might be
			simpler to be performed because you only have to solve
			merge conflicts
			once.
		
		Also, if your policy requires that all commits result in correct
			software you have to test
			all the rewritten
			commits
			since they are
			"rewritten"
			by the
			rebase
			algorithm. Since
			merge/rebase/cherry-pick are
			purely
			text-based
			and do
			not understand
			the semantics of these texts they
			can
			end up with
			logically
			incorrect
			results. Hence, it
			might be more
			efficient to merge
			a long feature branch into upstream
			instead of
			rebasing it since
			you only have to review and test
			the merge commit.
		
		<note>
			
				You can use the rebase command to change your Git repository
				history
				commits. This is called
				_interactive_
				rebase, see
				<xref linkend="interactive_rebase" />
				for information about this feature.
			
		</note>
	</section>
	<section id="rebase_bestpractice">
		<title>Good practice for rebase


		You should avoid using the Git rebase operation for changes
			which have been published in other Git repositories. The Git rebase
			operation creates new commit objects, this may
			confuse other
			developers using the
			existing commit objects.
		
		
			Assume that a user has a local feature branch and
			wants to push
			it to a
			branch on the remote repository. However, the
			branch has
			evolved and therefore
			pushing is not possible. Now it is
			good
			practice
			to fetch the
			latest state of the branch from the
			remote
			repository.
			Afterwards you
			rebase the local feature
			branch onto the
			remote
			tracking
			branch. This avoids an
			unnecessary
			merge commit.
			This
			rebasing of a
			local
			feature branch is
			also useful to
			incorporate
			the
			latest changes
			from
			remote into the
			local development,
			even if the
			user
			does not
			want to push
			right away.
		
		<tip>
			
				Rebasing and amending commits is safe as long as you do not
				push any of the changes
				involved in the rebase. For example, when you
				cloned a repository and
				worked in this local repository. Rebasing is
				a
				great way to keep the
				history clean before contributing back your
				modifications.
			
		</tip>

		<warning>
			
				In case you want to rewrite history for changes you have shared
				with
				others you need to use the
				`-f`
				parameter in your
				`git push`
				command and subsequently your colleagues have to use fetch -f to
				fetch the rewritten commits.
			
			[source,terminal]
----
include::./examples/rebase/forcedpush.txt[]
----
		</warning>
	</section>
</section>
