<section id="gitcommithooks" role="wrapper">
	<title>Git commit and other hooks</title>
	<section id="gitcommithooks_intro">
		<title>Usage of Git hooks</title>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>commit hooks</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<para>
			Git provides commit hooks, e.g., programs which can be executed
			at
			a pre-defined point during the work with the repository. For
			example, you can ensure that the commit message has a certain format
			or trigger an action after a push to the server.
		</para>
		<para>
			These programs
			are usually scripts and can be written in any
			language, e.g., as
			shell scripts
			or in Perl, Python etc. You can also
			implement a hook, for example, in C and use the resulting executables.
			Git calls the
			scripts
			based on
			a naming
			convention.
		</para>


	</section>
	<section id="gitcommithooks_clientserver">
		<title>Client and server side commit hooks</title>
		<para>
			Git provides hooks for the client and for the server side. On
			the
			server side you can use the
			<filename>pre-receive</filename>
			and
			<filename>post-receive</filename>
			script to check the input or to trigger actions after the commit. The
			usage of a server commit hook requires that you have access to the
			server. Hosting providers like GitHub or Bitbucket do not offer this
			access.
		</para>
		<para>
			If you create a new Git repository, Git creates example scripts in
			the
			<filename>.git/hooks</filename>
			directory. The example scripts end with
			<filename>.sample</filename>
			.
			To activate them make them executable and remove the
			<filename>.sample</filename>
			from the filename.
		</para>
		<para>
			The hooks are documented under the following URL:
			<ulink
				url="https://www.kernel.org/pub/software/scm/git/docs/githooks.html">Git hooks manual page</ulink>
			.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="gitcommithooks_restrictions">
		<title>Restrictions</title>
		<para>Not all Git server implementations support server side commit
			hooks. For example
			Gerrit (a Git server which also provides the
			ability to do code
			review) does not support hooks in this form. Also
			Github and
			Bitbucket do not support server hooks at the time of this
			writing.
		</para>
		<para>Local hooks in the local repository can be removed by the
			developer.
		</para>
	</section>

</section>