<section id="line_feedendings" role="wrapper">
	<title>Handling line endings on different platforms

	<section id="line_feedendings_platform">
		<title>Line endings of the different platforms

		
			LARSPRIMARYINDEX"line endings"LARSPRIMARYINDEX
		
		
			LARSPRIMARYINDEX"linefeed characters"LARSPRIMARYINDEX
		

		Every time a developer presses return on the keyboard an
			invisible character called a line ending is inserted. Unfortunately,
			different
			operating systems handle line endings differently.
		
		Linux and Mac use different line endings than Windows. Windows
			uses a carriage-return and a linefeed character (CRLF), while Linux
			and Mac
			only uses a linefeed character (LF). This becomes a problem if
			developers use different operating system to commit changes to a Git
			repository.
		
		To avoid commits because of line ending differences in your Git
			repository you should configure all clients to write the same line
			ending to the Git repository.
		

	</section>

	<section id="line_feedendings_convert">
		<title>Configuring line ending settings as developer
		On Windows systems you can tell Git to convert line endings
			during a checkout
			to CRLF and to convert them back to LF during
			commit.
			Use the
			following setting for this.
		

		[source,terminal]
----
include::./examples/linefeed/windows.txt[]
----

		On Linux and Mac you can tell Git to convert CRLF  to
			LF with the following setting. 
		
		[source,terminal]
----
include::./examples/linefeed/linux.txt[]
----

	</section>

	<section id="line_feedendings_gitattributes">
		<title>Configuring line ending settings per repository
		
			LARSPRIMARYINDEX".gitattributes
			"LARSPRIMARYINDEX
			LARSSECONDARY""LARSSECONDARY
		
		
			You can also configure the line ending handling per repository
			by
			adding a special
			_.gitattributes_
			file to the root folder of your Git repository. If this file is
			committed to the repository, it overrides the
			`core.autocrlf`
			setting of the individual developer.
		
		In this file you can configure Git to auto detect the line
			endings.
		
		<note>
			
				Not all graphical Git tools support the
				_.gitattributes_
				file, for example the Eclipse IDE does currently not support it. See
				<ulink url="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/show_bug.cgi?id=342372">Eclipse Bug report</ulink>
				.
			
		</note>
	</section>

</section>