<section id="gitworkflows" role="wrapper">
	<title>Typical Git workflow using separate repositories</title>
	<para> The following description highlights typical Git workflows.
	</para>
	<section id="gitworkflow_patch">
		<title>Providing a patch</title>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Git workflow</primary>
			<secondary>providing patches</secondary>
		</indexterm>
		<para> Git emphasizes the creation of branches for feature development
			or
			to create
			bug fixes. The following description lists a typical Git
			workflow for
			fixing a bug in your source code (files) and providing a
			patch for it. This patch contains the changes and can be used by
			another person to apply the changes to his local Git repository.
		</para>
		<para>This description assumes that the developer who creates the
			changes cannot push changes directly to the remote repository. For
			example you solve an issue in the source code of an open source
			project and want that the maintainer of the project to
			integrate this change into this repository.
		</para>
		<para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Clone the repository, in case you have not done that.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a new branch for the bug fix</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Modify the files (source code)</para>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>Commit changes to your branch </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create patch </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Send patch to another person or attach it to a bug report, so
						that is can be applied to the other Git repository
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
		<para>You may also want to commit several times during 3. and 4. and
			rebase your commits afterwards.
		</para>

	</section>

	<section id="gitworkflows_workingwithtworepositories">
		<title>Working with two repositories</title>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Git workflow</primary>
			<secondary>using two repositories</secondary>
		</indexterm>
		<para>Sometimes you want to add a second remote repository to your
			local Git repository and pull from and push to both repositories.
			The
			following example describes how to add another remote
			repository
			and
			exchange commits with both repositories.
		</para>
		<para>
			You can add another remote repository called
			<wordasword>remote_name</wordasword>
			via the following command.
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="bourne">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="../examples/addremote/step1.txt" />
			</programlisting>
		</para>

		<para>
			For merging the changes in
			<wordasword>mysecondrepo</wordasword>
			create a new branch called
			<wordasword>newbranch</wordasword>
			.
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="bourne">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="../examples/addremote/step2.txt" />
			</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>
			Afterwards you can pull from your new repository called
			<wordasword>mysecondrepo</wordasword>
			and push to your original repository, e.g., origin.
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="bourne">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="../examples/addremote/step3.txt" />
			</programlisting>
		</para>

	</section>
	<section id="gitworkflows_pullrequests">
		<title>Using pull requests</title>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Git workflow</primary>
			<secondary>providing pull requests</secondary>
		</indexterm>
		<para>Another very common Git workflow is the usage of pull requests.
			In this workflow a developer clones a repository and once he thinks
			he
			has something useful for another clone or the origin repository he
			sends the owner a pull request asking to merge his changes.
		</para>
		<para>A pull request can be seen as a notification which includes
			the
			information from which branch and URL the changes can be pulled
			and
			also the information to which URL and branch these changes should
			be
			pulled too.
		</para>
		<para>This workflow is actively promoted by the GitHub.com
			hosting
			platform but you can also provide the required information to
			someone
			via email.
		</para>
		<tip>
			<para>
				You can use the
				<code>git request-pull</code>
				command to generate a generic pull request which you may include
				into an email.
				See
				<ulink
					url="https://www.kernel.org/pub/software/scm/git/docs/git-request-pull.html">Git request-pull</ulink>
				for details.
			</para>
		</tip>
	</section>

</section>
