<section id="hosting_github" role="wrapper">
== GitHub

	<section id="hosting_github_what">
=== What is GitHub?
		<indexterm>
			<primary>GitHub</primary>
		</indexterm>

		
			GitHub
			is a popular hosting provider for Git repositories. GitHub
			provides also additional services around these repositories, for
			example an issue tracker for each repository, build server
			integration and more.
		
		
			GitHub supports that repositories can be cloned
			to a new Git
			repository hosted at Github. GitHub uses the term
			<wordasword>fork</wordasword>
			or
			<wordasword>forking</wordasword>
			for creating such clones.
		
		
			GitHub
			provides
			free hosting for publicly visible
			Git
			repositories.
			A
			public
			repository can be cloned by other people
			at
			any point in
			time.
		
		
			If the repository should not be visible to everyone, Git allows
			to create private repositories, but you must pay for this service a
			monthly rate.
			Private repository allows you to
			specify the
			people which
			have access
			to the
			repository and to define their access
			rights.
		
		
			GitHub can be found
			under the following
			URL.
		
		
			https://github.com">
				GitHub
			</ulink>
		

		
			If you create an account at GitHub, you can create a repository.
			After
			creating a repository at GitHub, you will get a description of
			all the
			commands you need
			to execute to upload your project to GitHub.
			Follow
			the
			instructions below.
		
		
			These instructions will be similar to the following commands.
		
		
			<programlisting language="bourne">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="./examples/github/example.txt" />
			</programlisting>
		

		
			GitHub allows you to use SSH based or HTTPS based authentication
			to
			access your
			repositories. To clone, pull or fetch from a public
			available repository no authentication is required.
		
	</section>

	<section id="github_createrepo">
=== Create repository in GitHub
		
			Once you create a user at Github, you can create a new public
			repository. For example the following screenshots demonstrate the
			creation of
			the
			<wordasword>de.vogella.git.github</wordasword>
			repository.
		

		
image::github10.png" scale="30" />

				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Creating GitHub repository step 1</phrase>
				</textobject>
			</mediaobject>

		
		
image::github20.png" scale="30" />

				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Creating GitHub repository step 2</phrase>
				</textobject>
			</mediaobject>

		


		After creation of your new repository GitHub displays the
			information what you have to
			do if you want to connect to this
			repository via the command line. As
			we are going to use
			EGit you can
			ignore this information.
		
	</section>
	<section id="hosting_github_mergingpullrequests">
=== Merging pull request at GitHub
		<indexterm>
			<primary>GitHub</primary>
			<secondary>Merging pull requests</secondary>
		</indexterm>
		
			GitHub uses
			<wordasword>Pull requests</wordasword>
			for contributions.
		
		The typical workflow in GitHub is to fork a repository, create
			changes in your fort and send a pull request to the origin repository
			via the
			GitHub webinterface.
		
		
			GitHub makes is easy to fork a repository via its web interface.
			Simply click the
			<guibutton>Fork</guibutton>
			button of a repository of your choice.
		
		
image::github_pullrequest10.png"
						scale="40" />
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Forking a GitHub repository</phrase>
				</textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		
		
			You can now clone this fork to your local development
			environment and push the changes to this fork at GitHub.
		
		
			Afterwards you can create a pull request for the repository you
			forked
			from. Your
			repository is the fork as highlighted in the
			screenshot. Press
			<guilabel>Pull Requests</guilabel>
			to see existing and create new pull requests.
		
		
image::github_pullrequest20.png"
						scale="30" />
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Creating a pull request for Github, Part 1</phrase>
				</textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		

		
			Click
			<guilabel>New pull request</guilabel>
			to create a new one.
		
		
image::github_pullrequest30.png"
						scale="30" />
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Creating a pull request for Github, Part 2</phrase>
				</textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		
		
			On the next screen you can specify the direction of the pull request
			and the branches if you select the
			<guilabel>Edit</guilabel>
			button.
		
		
image::github_pullrequest40.png"
						scale="30" />
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Creating a pull request from Github, Part 3</phrase>
				</textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		

		If the owner of the repository accepts your pull request
			your
			changes are integrated into the original repository.
		
	</section>

</section>