<section id="groovy" role="wrapper">
== Groovy
	<section id="groovy_overview">
=== What is Groovy?
		
			http://www.groovy-lang.org/">Groovy</ulink> is an optionally typed, dynamic language that runs on
			the JVM. It is
			tightly integrated with the Java
			programming language. Groovy describes itself as feature-rich and Java-friendly
			language.
		
		
			Groovy
			source code is compiled into Java byte-code by the Groovy compiler. To run Groovy code in
			a Java
			virtual machine,
			only the Groovy
			`JAR`
			file must be present in the classpath at runtime.

		
		Groovy
			supports standard
			Java constructs including
			annotations,
			generics,
			static imports,
			enums, varargs and lambda
			expression. It provides lots of
			simplifications
			compared to the Java
			programming language
			and
			advanced language
			features as
			properties,
			closures, dynamic methods, the Meta Object Protocol (MOP), native
			support
			for
			lists,
			maps,
			regular
			expressions,
			duck typing
			and the
			elvis
			operator.
		

	<section id="groovy_types">
=== Groovy classes and scripts 
		
			A Groovy source files ends with the
			`.groovy`
			extension. This file can contain a Groovy script or a Groovy class. A
			Groovy script is a code listing which does not
			include a class
			definition. Groovy scripts are converted at compile time to a class
			which extends the
			`groovy.lang.Script`
			class.
		
		The classical "Hello world" program can be written as a short
			Groovy
			script.
[source,java]
----
include::res/first/HelloWorld.groovy[]
----
		





	<section id="groovy_compatibility">
=== Compatibility with Java
		
			Groovy runs inside the JVM and can use Java libraries. Every Groovy
			type is a subclass of
			`java.lang.Object`
			.
		
		
			Groovy code can call Java code and Java code can call Groovy
			code.
			Every Groovy class is compiled into a Java class and
			you can use the
			`new`
			operator in Java to create instances of the Groovy class. This
			instance can be used to call methods or to pass as
			parameter to a
			fitting Java method. Groovy classes can extend Java classes and Java
			classes can also extend Groovy
			classes.
		

		 Groovy is
			almost compatible with the Java 7 sytax, e.g., almost every valid Java 7
			construct
			is valid
			Groovy code. This
			makes the
			migration to Groovy
			for
			a
			Java
			programmer
			relatively smooth.
		
		Groovy does currently not support Java 8 lambda expressions.

	<section id="groovy_feature">
=== Reasons to use Groovy
		
			Groovy focus on simplicity and ease of use as its leading
			principle.
			This makes using Groovy very productive.
		
		
			The enhancements of Groovy compared to Java can be classified as:
			
				<listitem>
					Groovy language features
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					Groovy specific libraries
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					Additional methods to existing Java classes by the Groovy
						Developer
						Kit, this is commonly known as the Groovy
						JDK.
					
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		
		
			The following list contains
			some of the example how Groovy archives
			this.
			

				<listitem>
					
						Simplification - Groovy does not require semicolons at the end of
						statements. The
						`return`
						keyword can be left out, by default Groovy returns the last
						expression of the method, top
						level parentheses can be
						left out,
						the
						`public`
						keyword can be left out, it is the default in Groovy. It also
						allows
						optional typing.
					
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					Flexibility - Groovy allows to change classes and methods at
						runtime, e.g.
						if a method is called which does not
						exist on a
						class, the class
						can intercept this call and react to it. This
						allows for example
						that Groovy provides a
						very flexible builder
						pattern.
					
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					Ease of use - Groovy has list, maps and regular expressions
						directly
						build
						into
						the language.
					
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					Simplification in I/O - parsing and creating XML, JSON and
						files is very simple with
						Groovy.
					
				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		



	<section id="groovy_imports">
=== Imports in Groovy 
		
			Groovy automatically imports the following packages and classes which
			can be used in Groovy without specifying the
			package name.
			
				<listitem>
					groovy.lang.*
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					groovy.util.*
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					java.lang.*
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					java.util.*
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					java.net.*
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					java.io.*
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					java.math.BigInteger
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					java.math.BigDecimal
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		
		
			Groovy allows that an import is shortened for later access, e.g.,
			`import javax.swing.WindowConstants as WC`
			.
		

